Vivek Kumar

Lead Frontend Engineer

Contact

Address

Chennai, India 600019

Phone

9840092120

E-mail

vivek4neel@gmail.com

Github

<u>https://github.com/VivekNe</u> <u>el</u>

Stack overflow

https://stackoverflow.com/u sers/3052300/vivek-neel

Twitter

https://twitter.com/viveknee 55

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ir/vivek-neel-65585b103/

Portfolio

https://me.vivekneel.vercel.app/

Skills

React, React-Native,
Javascript, next-js, remix,
monorepo, material-ui,
redux, relay, leadership,
html, css, unit-testing,
Cypress, CI/CD, building,
Typescript, responsive
website, building ui
following the material
design guidelines, building
highly performant web
pages for good seo ranking

An expert in react, react-native, relay and an open source enthusiast. I have a total of 5.5 years of experience working professionally. I build web and mobile applications using cutting edge technologies. I also build libraries and own apps during my free time. My approach to software development is developer-supportive, balancing technical needs, team skills, and product requirements. Mentoring and pair-programming are really rewarding, and I excel at planning and developing solutions for longer-term timescales

Work History

2018-11 -Current

Lead Frontend Engineer

Memorang Labs Private Limited, Chennai

- Refactored and recreated memorang from scratch. I set up the project using monorepo architecture which has web, mobile applications and a common module used across the apps
- Created several whitelabel mobile apps and websites for partners
- Solved some complex UI/UX, for instance: A page with dynamic n number of editors supporting rich text formatting and doing efficient api calls on each action.
- All the apps are built using the latest/popular framework, for instance: next js, latest react, remix etc. Also all the component have unit-test, integration-test written using Jest, CypressJs and a well typed code using Typescript
- I lead everything related to frontend

2016-06 -2018-10

Frontend Developer

Qube cinema technologies, Chennai

- I refactored the Justickets mobile app for qube cinema
- Handled end-to-end feature developments, also integrate multiple payment providers
- Created Moviebuff application from scratch, has complex feature such monthly calendar, yearly infinite calendar etc

2015-09 -2016-06

Programmer Analyst Trainee

Cognizant technology solution, Chennai

• Worked on adpart android application

Education

2011-07 -2015-08

B.Tech: Chemical Engineering

SSN College of Engineering - Chennai, India